Chris Pappas

Full Stack Developer seeking a role working with great people, interesting tech and solving valuable problems, and using my wide range of skills and experience as a "force multiplier" to help my team succeed.

I would appreciate the opportunity to chat more with you, about how my knowledge and abilities line up with what you're looking for. Please reach out at work@chrispappas.dev or message me on LinkedIn.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Production Engineer - Observability Shopify, Remote

Nov 2021 - May 2023

- IC on the Observability UX team, building and supporting custom Grafana plugin and GraphQL API development
- Implementing an O11y solution using Grafana and Prometheus, integrating with all production systems across Shopify including Trace search, a Metrics explorer and Alerting system, dashboard annotations and a custom variable editor using metadata from BigQuery
- Maintained our customized Grafana fork, keeping it current with upstream releases of Grafana
- Extensive Grafana plugin development, with a Prometheus query builder, custom variable builder, and dashboard annotation editor, using Golang and React with Typescript
- Built a Kafka consumer using Golang and Sarama to ingest thousands of deploy events per day and provide them as dashboard annotations
- Contributed to a large GraphQL API backend driving the Metrics systems using Golang and MySQL/BigQuery
- CI using Buildkite and Docker including Unit and Acceptance Tests, Linting, and deployment to Kubernetes

Key Tech: Golang, React, Typescript, GraphQL, MySQL, BigQuery, Grafana, Prometheus, Kafka, Kubernetes

Senior Software Engineer

APOLLO Insurance, Remote

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

- AWS Lambda Serverless using NodeJS, AWS DynamoDB and React
- Insurance product development and implementation, working with the Underwriting and Product teams to implement policy generation
- Cross-functional team including Product Managers, Design, Development, Underwriting and Policy

Key Tech: NodeJS, AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, React

CONTACT INFO

Winnipeg, Canada work@chrispappas.dev linkedin.com/in/chris-pappas github.com/chrispappas chrispappas.dev

TOP SKILLS

Golang, PHP, Node, Laravel, Hugo React, Vue, Typescript, GraphQL SQL, Elasticsearch, DynamoDB Git, DevOps, Kubernetes, Linux Nginx, Apache, Varnish DNS, Cloudflare, Hosting

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack dev with experience across a wide range of technologies and industries, and a passion for learning new things and making new connections. I have worked in organizations from 10 to 10,000, on teams of 3 to 13+, and one attribute I'm often credited with and proud of, is being a great team player.

I am an experienced people leader, but my real love is writing code and seeing it work. I believe in unit and automated testing, but I'm not a TDD zealot. My Git history is clean and well-commented, and I appreciate a really well-crafted Pull Request or Issue Description as much as a detailed Readme file. Updating documentation is something I have incorporated into my development cycle, and I have thanked myself many times for just writing it down.

I love **solving new problems** and **fixing what's broken**.

What should I do next?

Staff Software Engineer

Glacier FarmMedia, Winnipeg, Canada

Nov 2017 - Jul 2021

- Tech Lead for the AgDealer.com online platform, a top Canadian agricultural equipment catalog
- Team Lead for in-house developers and external consultants, working with Sales and Lead Generation teams
- Continuous ingestion of new listings from partner dealers, indexing descriptions and metadata for full-text and faceted search, image resizing/watermarking and serving via CDN
- Built on Laravel with PHP, using Elasticsearch and MS SQL Server, REST API, Async Queue Workers, Lambda NodeJS image processing, and VueJS for the UI and Admin interfaces.
- Server administration on AWS including RDS database management, Linux system admin, Nginx and Apache configuration. DevOps implementation using Gitlab CI with custom runners. Local development platform using Docker and Docker-compose.

Key Tech: PHP, Laravel, Elasticsearch, MS SQL Server, VueJS, AWS Lambda

Senior Developer Team Lead

Bold Commerce, Winnipeg, Canada

May 2016 - Nov 2017

- Team lead for E-commerce R&D Projects using Youtube video player with Mithril and Vuejs based overlay
- Laravel/PHP REST API development using MySQL
- Kubernetes and CI DevOps for production and staging deployments

Associate Manager

IG Wealth Management, Winnipeg, Canada

Nov 2014 - May 2016

- · Managed a team of front-end developers in the Marketing Department
- Content management for the main corporate website, investor relations site and large-scale employee intranet sites
- Custom application development using Angular and VueJS

Front-End Web Developer

Tipping Canoe, Winnipeg, Canada

Aug 2011 - Oct 2014

- Web developer at Tipping Canoe, specializing in front-end design and implementation across many web properties including HotUKDeals.com
- Developed and implemented a full SASS component library for the UI and UX of HotUKDeals, used by myself and the implementation team to rebuild and redesign the site

EDUCATION

University of Manitoba

B.Sc. (Computer Science)

Apr 2009

Elasticsearch

Engineer I & II

2019